Guide to the May Anti-Slavery manuscript collection, 1749-1933.
May Anti-Slavery manuscript collection
- Series IV. Correspondence and Documents from Other Abolitionists
  - G-May, Samuel, Jr.
    - Love, Alfred Henry, July 11, 1860 (Box 17, Folder 52)
      Letter/s to Mott, James and McKim, James Miller
    - Love, William De Loss, February 21, 1866 (Box 17, Folder 53)
    - Low, James, October 2, 1867 (Box 17, Folder 54)
    - Low, Walter, May 10, 1869 (Box 17, Folder 55)
    - Lowe, Charles, March 17, 1866 (Box 17, Folder 56)
    - Lowell, Josephine Shaw, 1866-1887 (Box 17, Folder 57)
      Letter/s to Harris, George William; McKim, James Miller
    - Lyon, Mary E., July 20, 1866 (Box 17, Folder 59)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendations from Kingsley, E.M. and Wright, Thomas G.
    - Lynch, Annette, August 29, 1867 (Box 17, Folder 58)
      Letter concerning a teaching position; Recommendations signed by Ketchum, R.B.; Mattorn, L.; Mitchell, Titus M.; Seymour, Daniel; 5 paychecks
    - Lyons, Theresa, 1868-1869 (Box 17, Folder 60)
    - Macaulay, Zachary, 1819-1821 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Macomber, A.E., 1867-1868 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Macy, Mary, January 9, 1868 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Manly, R.M., 1866-1870 (Box 18, Folder 4-6)
      Receipts; Abbott, Lyman; Lowell, Josephine Shaw (Mrs. C.R.); McKim, James Miller; Shipherd, Jacob R.; unknown
      Hancock, Ann B.; Manly, Mrs. R.M.
    - Manly, Mrs. R.M., February 18, 1869 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      Receipt; 1 paycheck
    - Mann, John S., 1866 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Mann, M.W., 1866 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Mann, Mary Tyler, Undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Mario, Jessie, April 19, 1860 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Marsh, Ella E., 1868-1869 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Martinique, June 25, 1775 (Box 18, Folder 13)
      Letter/s to Begins "Aujourd'huy vingt cinq juin mil sept cent soixante quinze de rellevee…"
    - Masury, Mrs. D.G., November 1, 1866 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Mathews, James, November 14, 1825 (Box 18, Folder 14.5)
    - Matlcok, Lucius C., November 5, 1861 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - May, Abby W., May 24, 1869 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - May, Bonnie, 1854-1858 (Box 18, Folder 17)
      Letter/s to May, Joseph; May, John
    - May, Charles S., February 19, 1866 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - May, Charlotte C., 1844-1865 (Box 18, Folder 19)
      Letter/s to May, Joseph; May, Samuel Joseph
    - May, Jonah Rupell, Undated (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - May, Joseph, 1846-1894 (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
      Documents dealing with May's will and estate (facsimiles); Harris, George William; May, Hatty; McKim, James Miller; May, Samuel Joseph
    - May, Lucretia F., 1828-1865 (Box 18, Folder 21-43)
      Letter/s to J.E.; May, Johnny; May, Joseph; May, Col. Joseph; May, Samuel Joseph
      Coffin, Peter
    - May, Mary Ann, November 29, 1827 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - May, Samuel, Jr., 1858-1895 (Box 19, Folder 4-18)
      Letter/s to Cousin of May, Samuel J.; Frank; Fiske, Willard; Harris, George William; McKim, James Miller; Rickards, Elias
      Abbott, Lyman; Stevenson, Hannah
  - May, Samuel Joseph
    - May, Samuel Joseph, Undated (Box 19, Folder 19)
      Three copies of engraved portrait
    - May, Samuel Joseph, Undated (Box 19, Folder 20)
      Letter/s to May, Joseph
    - May, Samuel Joseph, Undated (Box 19, Folder 21)
      Hand drawn plan of Brooklyn, Connecticut
    - May, Samuel Joseph, Undated (Box 19, Folder 21)
      Engraving of Scott, Mrs. Dorothy
    - May, Samuel Joseph, Undated (Box 19, Folder 21)
      Photograph of May, Samuel Joseph
    - May, Samuel Joseph, Undated (Box 19, Folder 21)
      Photograph of Rice, Mrs. Thomas
    - May, Samuel Joseph, Undated (Box 19, Folder 21)
      Note by Briggs, Rev. George
    - May, Samuel Joseph, Undated (Box 19, Folder 21)
      Photograph of Southboro Tunbridge Wells
    - May, Samuel Joseph, Undated (Box 19, Folder 21)
      Copies of engravings of May
    - Stepanek, Catherine, 1958-1959 (Box 19, Folder 21)
      Letter/s to Miss Wilkinson
    - May, Samuel Joseph, 1834-05-1834-06 (Box 19, Folder 22-23)
    - May, Samuel Joseph, 1835-02-1835-09 (Box 19, Folder 24-32)
    - May, Samuel Joseph, June 14, 1842 (Box 19, Folder 33)
      Letter/s to May, Samuel Jr.
    - May, Samuel Joseph, January 27, 1845 (Box 19, Folder 34)
      Letter/s to Putnam, Hiram; Spencer, Thomas; Wilkinson, John
    - May, Samuel Joseph, February 5, 1845 (Box 19, Folder 35)
      Letter/s to Putnam, Hiram; Wilkinson, John
    - May, Samuel Joseph, February 12, 1845 (Box 19, Folder 36)
      Letter/s to Clary, Lyman; Phelps, Dudley P.
    - May, Samuel Joseph, March 4, 1845 (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - May, Samuel Joseph, 1845-03-1845-04 (Box 19, Folder 38-40)
      Letters/toPhelps, Dudley P.
    - May, Samuel Joseph, August 2, 1848 (Box 19, Folder 41)
      Letters/tounknown
    - May, Samuel Joseph, January 7, 1850 (Box 19, Folder 42)
      Letters/toThe Unitarian Congregational Society of Syracuse
    - May, Samuel Joseph, January 26, 1850 (Box 19, Folder 43)
      Letter/s to Putnam, Hiram; Wilkinson, John; Williston, Charles H.
    - May, Samuel Joseph, 1853-06-08-1853-06-09 (Box 19, Folder 44-45)
      Letter/s to Parrish, Joseph
    - May, Samuel Joseph, 1853-08-09 (Box 19, Folder 46)
      Letter/s to Still, Peter
    - May, Samuel Joseph, 1853-11-02 (Box 19, Folder 47)
    - May, Samuel Joseph, 1853-07-15 (Box 19, Folder 48)
      Certification of the identity of Still, Peter
    - May, Samuel Joseph, 1854-10-07 (Box 19, Folder 49)
    - May, Samuel Joseph, 1854-05-09 (Box 19, Folder 50)
    - May, Samuel Joseph, 1855-03-09 (Box 19, Folder 51)
    - May, Samuel Joseph, 1855-04-27 (Box 19, Folder 52)
      Letter/s to Pickard, Kate E. R.
    - May, Samuel Joseph, 1857-11-10 (Box 19, Folder 53)
      Letter/s to Moncure, Daniel Conway
    - May, Samuel Joseph, 1860-08-19 (Box 19, Folder 53A)
      Letter/s to Sanborn, H. B.
    - May, Samuel Joseph, 1863-03-24 (Box 19, Folder 54)
      Letter/s to Mrs. Willson
    - May, Samuel Joseph, 1863-06-15 (Box 19, Folder 55)
      Letter/s to The Unitarian Congregational Society of Syracuse
    - May, Samuel Joseph, 1866-02-20 (Box 19, Folder 56)
    - May, Samuel Joseph, 1866-07-1866-08 (Box 19, Folder 57-60)
    - May, Samuel Joseph, 1866-08-16 (Box 19, Folder 61)
      Letter/s to Greene, Jennie
    - May, Samuel Joseph, 1867-05-1867-06 (Box 19, Folder 62-64)
    - May, Samuel Joseph, 1867-06-20 (Box 19, Folder 63)
    - May, Samuel Joseph, 1869-05-19 (Box 19, Folder 64)
  - McCl-McKe
    - McClellan, Carrie, August 4, 1866 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendation signed by A.B. White, S.D. Crothers, F.W. Pierson, and R.C. Kinkead
    - McClintock, John, 1847-1866 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - James R. McDonald & Co., March 17, 1866 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - McGregor, James W., February 15, 1866 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - McKay, C.E., September 19, 1867 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - McKersh, J.P., January 14, 1867 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - McKim, James Miller
    Search also under his name for letters written to McKim from others.
    Correspondents include: Alvord, J.W.; Atkinson, Thomas; Brown, Mrs. Mary Ann Day (Mrs. John Brown); Chase, C. Thurston; Estes, E.C.; Furey, John G.; Hancock, Clayton; Howard, Oliver Otis; May, Samuel, Jr.; Pillsbury, Parker; Redpath, James; Shaw, Francis George; Smith, Samuel Arthur; Stradling, Thomas; Sumner, Charles; Walden, John Morgan; Ward, George Cabot; Webb, R.D.; Whipple, Rev. George; Miss Wisham
    Arranged chronologically
    - Card catalogue of James Miller McKim correspondence (Box 8)
    - McKim, James Miller, Undated (Box 20, Folder 7-16)
      Calendar of letters; Alvord, J.W.; Atkinson, Thomas; Brown, Mrs. Mary Ann Day (Mrs. John Brown); Chase, C. Thurston; Estes, E.C.; Furey, John G.; Hancock, Clayton; Howard, Oliver Otis; May, Samuel, Jr.; Pillsbury, Parker; Redpath, James; Shaw, Francis George; Smith, Samuel Arthur; Stradling, Thomas; Sumner, Charles; Walden, John Morgan; Ward, George Cabot; Webb, R.D.; Whipple, Rev. George; Miss Wisham; unknown
      American Freedmen's Aid Commission; Parrish, Joseph; Wilde, Lizzie H.
    - McKim, James Miller, 1849 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - McKim, James Miller, 1858 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - McKim, James Miller, 1860 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - McKim, James Miller, 1862 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - McKim, James Miller, 1863 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - McKim, James Miller, 1864 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - McKim, James Miller, 1865 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - McKim, James Miller, 1866 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - McKim, James Miller, 1867 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - McKim, James Miller, 1868 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Wood engraving of McKim's daughter, Lucy Garrison McKim (Box M.S. box, Folder 1)
      Formerly on display in the A.D. White library
  - McKim, John-Q
    - McKim, John L., 1861 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - McKim Bros. & Co., January 29, 1866 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - McKinney, Mordecai, 1860 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - McMillan, Samuel James Renwick, February 24, 1866 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - McPherson, I.H., April 18, 1798 (Box 20, Folder 20)
      Letter/s to Mr. Stone
    - Mellen, L.F., 1865-1867 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Mendenhall, Isaac, May 5, 1861 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Merrick, Caroline H., 1866 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Merrick, Chloe, October 15, 1868 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Miles, Henry Adolphus, 1866 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Milligan, A.M., September 11, 1861 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Mississippi Chickasaw County Probate Court, 1856-1860 (Box 20, Folder 27-30)
      Documents of indenture
      Woodruff, Edwin Hamlin
    - Mitchell, Charles B., November 24, 1853 (Box 20, Folder 31)
      Indenture deeding slaves to James Johnston
    - Mitchell, William Forster, 1866-1869 (Box 20, Folder 32-35)
      Letter/s to Albright, Arthur; Hodgkins, John; Lowell, Josephine Shaw (Mrs. C.R.); McKim, James Miller; unknown
      Ward, George Cabot
    - G.I. Mix & Co., March 7, 1867 (Box 20, Folder 36)
      List of goods
    - M'Lanlin, C.D., October 16, 1867- (Box 20, Folder 37)
      Letter/s to Freedmen's Commission
    - Moody, Loring, November 19, 1865 (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - Moore, H.H., 1866 (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - Moore, Joseph, July 6, 1861 (Box 20, Folder 40)
    - Moore, R.G., January 12, 1869 (Box 20, Folder 41)
      Receipt for S.A. Bond
      Crews, J.B.
    - Morgan, Fanny A., 1869 (Box 20, Folder 42)
      Receipts; 4 paychecks
    - Morgan, Thomas Herwood, December 25, 1867 (Box 20, Folder 43)
    - Morris, Charles M., January 10, 1866 (Box 20, Folder 44)
    - Morris, M.L., August 20, 1866 (Box 20, Folder 45)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendation from Kimball, John
    - Morse, Charles, November 26, 1867 (Box 20, Folder 46)
      Letter/s to R.B. Mason
    - Moss, Lemuel, May 1, 1866 (Box 20, Folder 47)
      Letter/s to Cor. Sec'y Am. U. & F.C.
    - Mott, James, 1837-1861 (Box 20, Folder 48)
      Letter/s to Atkinson, Thomas; McKim, James Miller; Stradling, Thomas
    - Mott, Lucretia Coffin, 1834-1861 (Box 20, Folder 49)
    - Mullen, William J., November 3, 1858 (Box 20, Folder 50)
    - Mulvany, Ellen P., November 6, 1867 (Box 20, Folder 51)
    - Murdock, J.N., 1869 (Box 20, Folder 52)
      Receipt; 1 paycheck; Collins, Ellen
    - Naylor, Benjamin, October 13, 1867 (Box 20, Folder 53)
    - Needham, J. Fields, 1867 (Box 20, Folder 54)
    - Needles, John, August 10, 1861 (Box 20, Folder 55)
    - Nellis, Maggie, August 27, 1866 (Box 20, Folder 56)
      Recommendation for a teaching position from Sampson, Sarah A.
    - C.A. Nelson & Co., November 1, 1868 (Box 20, Folder 57)
    - New York State Anti-Slavery Society, September 10, 1852 (Box 20, Folder 58)
      Printed circular
    - Newell, Robert R., 1866 (Box 20, Folder 59)
    - Newsome, W.D., August 12, 1866 (Box 20, Folder 60)
    - Newton, A.E., 1866-1868 (Box 20, Folder 61-62)
      Letter/s to Kennedy, Crammond; McKim, James Miller; unknown
      Smith, Josephine F.; Wheeler, Addison
    - Newton, Frances, July 9, 1866 (Box 20, Folder 63)
      Letter/s to Recommendation for a teaching position from Williams, Frances E.
    - Nichols, Frederick B., November 14, 1849 (Box 20, Folder 63.5)
    - Nichols, W.A., April 30, 1866 (Box 20, Folder 64)
    - Nichols, W.S., June 19, 1866 (Box 20, Folder 65)
    - Nickens, Mary M., 1868-1869 (Box 20, Folder 66)
    - Nickerson, D.G., January 18, 1868 (Box 20, Folder 67)
    - Nixon, William Penn, May 5, 1866 (Box 20, Folder 68)
      Letter/s to Walden, John Morgan
    - Norris, Emma, 1870 (Box 20, Folder 69)
      Receipt; 4 paychecks
    - Northrup, G.E., July 1, 1867 (Box 20, Folder 70)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendation from Hitchcock, R.D.
    - Noyes, George F., August 26, 1867 (Box 20, Folder 71)
    - Nyce, B.M., June 7, 1866 (Box 20, Folder 72)
    - Oakley & Mason, October 15, 1868 (Box 20, Folder 73)
      Itemized receipt for Freedman's Association
    - Odell, Dora and Selma, August 16, 1866 (Box 20, Folder 74)
    - Ogilby, Charles, August 23, 1859 (Box 20, Folder 75)
    - Oglesby, Richard James, 1868 (Box 20, Folder 76)
    - Oliver, Mary Ellen, September 4, 1866 (Box 20, Folder 77)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendation from Rhoads, James E.
    - Olmsted, Frederick Law, 1866-1872 (Box 20, Folder 78)
      Shipherd, Jacob R.
    - Orlofte, G., July 12, 1861 (Box 20, Folder 79)
      Letter/s to Pennsylvania Anty (sic) slavery Society
    - Orr, James Lawrence, November 15, 1866 (Box 20, Folder 80)
      Letter/s to Scott, Robert Kingston
      Hays, Weston
    - Orton, Caroline S., August 1866 (Box 20, Folder 81)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendations from Barker, E.D.; Hall, George; Leavitt, Joshua; Johnson, Oliver; Bidwell, W.H.; Guy, Samuel S.; Orton, J.R.; Pompilly, J.T.
    - Orton, May E., August 30, 1867 (Box 20, Folder 82)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendations from Barker, E.D.; Beecher, Henry Ward; Emmett, M.H.; Guy, Samuel S.; Pierce, Nehemiah P.; Rouget, Peter; Smythe, H.A.
    - Osbourne, M.S., February 3, 1866 (Box 20, Folder 83)
    - Osgood, Lucy, 1844-1872 (Box 20, Folder 84-101)
      Letter/s to Child, Lydia Maria; Lucy; unknown
    - Owen, Fred W., April 2, 1866 (Box 20, Folder 102)
    - Owen, Robert Dale, March 3, 1867 (Box 20, Folder 103)
    - Owens, Horace F., June 27, 1869 (Box 20, Folder 104)
    - Page, John R., September 13, 1866 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      Letter/s to Woolsy, James J.
    - Paine, C.G.G., May 7, 1866 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      Clemmer, M.K.
    - Palmer, Jennie B., August 23, 1866 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendations from Kerr, George and McHarg, Harriet B.
    - Palmer, John R., July 9, 1867 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Parker, Caleb, September 8, 1866 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Parker, Martha A., 1869 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      Receipts; 2 paychecks
    - Parker, Theodore, 1850-1860 (Box 21, Folder 7-8)
      Letter/s to McKim, James Miller; Smith, Gerrit
    - Parkman, C.M., December 14, 1866 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Parkman, John, 1866-1869 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Parrish, Joseph, 1839-1866 (Box 21, Folder 11-12)
      May, Samuel Joseph
    - Parvin, Robert J., 1866-1867 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Patterson, J.E., August 17, 1867 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Patterson, Robert Wilson, 1865-1867 (Box 21, Folder 15)
      Letter/s to McKim, James Miller; Poe, Adam
      Kennedy, Thomas
    - Paul, J. Marshall, April 30, 1866 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Paul, May S., June 11, 1867 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Payne, Daniel Alexander, 1866-1867 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Payne, George F., 1869-1870 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Payne, Sebastian, July 2, 1869 (Box 21, Folder 20)
      Receipt; 7 paychecks
    - Payne, William Oscar, December 22, 1869 (Box 21, Folder 21)
      Recommendation for a teaching position from Loveridge, P.H.; 5 paychecks
    - Pease, Henry Roberts, 1867 (Box 21, Folder 22)
      Letter/s to Holmes, H.B.; Mrs. S.O. Snelling
    - Peck, Jesse Truesdell, 1866 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Peck, John, October 30, 1860 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Peet, Harriet E., August 17, 1866 (Box 21, Folder 25)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendations from Pullman, Joseph and Trowbridge, P.M.
    - Peirce, Warren, Undated (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Peirce, William L., 1860 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Pennypacker, E.T., 1861 (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Pepper, Calvin, March 10, 1866 (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Perkins, B.F., January 8, 1868 (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Perkins, Fannie A. and Mary Eliza, August 18, 1866 (Box 21, Folder 31)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendations from Brickett, L.H.; Foster, William H.; Hillman, Thos.; Holt, Chas. L.; 3 paychecks; 3 receipts
    - Perkins, Joseph, 1866-1867 (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - Perkins, W., January 13, 1868 (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - Perrin, Eugenia, November 26, 1867 (Box 21, Folder 34)
    - Perry, Martin, October 6, 1866 (Box 21, Folder 35)
    - Perry, Mary E., September 14, 1865 (Box 21, Folder 36)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendations from Barrett, E.S. and one unknown person
    - Peters, Joshua, Jr., March 26, 1832 (Box 21, Folder 36.5)
      Certificate of Freedom
    - Phelps, Millie, April 27, 1867 (Box 21, Folder 37)
    - Phelps, Myron, 1867-1868 (Box 21, Folder 38)
    - Phenix, Laura V., 1869 (Box 21, Folder 39)
      Receipts; 5 patchecks
    - Philadelphia First African Baptist Church, 1831-1835 (Box 21, Folder 40)
      Letter/s to Gibbs, Nathaniel's Memorandum Book of the Weekly Fund of the First African Baptist Church
    - Philadelphia Secret Vigilance Committee, December 11, 1860 (Box 21, Folder 41)
      Letter/s to Proprietors of Anti-Slavery Office
    - Philleo, Prudence Crandall, 1832-1885 (Box 21, Folder 42)
      Letter/s to Garrison, Wendell Phillips; Jocelyn, Simeon Smith
    - Phillips, E.B., 1867 (Box 21, Folder 43)
    - Phillips, Joseph, 1829-1830 (Box 21, Folder 44)
      Extract of prison notes written during incarceration of twelve months on Antigua
    - Phillips, Thomas, 1867-1870 (Box 21, Folder 45-46)
      Copy of resolution passed at a meeting of the Executive Committee; McKim, James Miller
    - Phillips, Wendell, 1842-1867 (Box 21, Folder 47-63)
      Letter/s to McKim, James Miller; May, Samuel Joseph; unknown
      Wilson, W.P.
    - Pickard, Kate E.R., 1852-1866 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      Letter/s to May, Samuel Joseph; Letters from May to Pickard and Still, Peter referring to Pickard's publication of Still's biography
    - Pierce, Edward Lillie, 1863-1867 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Pierce, R., 1868-1869 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Pierpont, John, 1847-1852 (Box 22, Folder 4-11)
    - Pillsbury, Parker, 1856-1883 (Box 22, Folder 12-12.5)
    - Pine, Hillyer & Co., December 1, 1869 (Box 22, Folder 13)
      Itemized receipt for Lowell, C.R.
    - Pinkerton, John J., October 12, 1860 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Platt, E.E., December 28, 1867 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Pollard, Sabin & Co., April 19, 1869 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Poole, William Frederick, February 15, 1866 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Pope, George A., 1866 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Post, Amy, May 7, 1867 (Box 22, Folder 19)
      Letter/s to Freedmans Relief Association
    - Powell, Aaron Macy, 1860-1867 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Powell, George May, January 3, 1866 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Powell, William P., March 2, 1861 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Power, Joshua, January 14, 1800 (Box 22, Folder 23)
      Letter/s to Stone, M.G.
    - Pratt, Ezra B., May 28, 1866 (Box 22, Folder 24)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendations from Hull, Dwight P. and Newcomb, M.S.
    - Pratt, G.W., 1867 (Box 22, Folder 25)
      Letter/s to Col. Cuson; McKim, James Miller
    - Pratt, John W., September 16, 1866 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Preston, Harriet E., February 1869 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Price, Arthur, 1844 (Box 22, Folder 28)
      Letter/s to McKim, James Miller (Miller, John J.)
    - Pride, O.J., July 23, 1866 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Pringle, Charles, January 15, 1868 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - Proctor, W.L., January 8, 1867 (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - Pugh, Sarah, March 18, 1866 (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - Purvis, Robert, 1860-1866 (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Pusey, C.W., March 11, 1861 (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - Putnam, Hiram, 1844-1850 (Box 22, Folder 35-37)
      Letter/s to May, Samuel Joseph (facsimiles)
    - Quackenbush, Stephen Platt, 1866 (Box 22, Folder 38)
    - Quincy, Edmund, 1845-1863 (Box 22, Folder 39-40)
      Letter/s to Chapman, Maria Weston; McKim, James Miller
    - Quinn, Harriette B., 1864-1866 (Box 22, Folder 41)
      Applications for a teaching position; Recommendations from Everts, Orpheus and Hopkins, Samuel A.
  - R-Y
    - Randolph, B.F., July 18, 1866 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendation from Lewis, T. Willard
    - Rankin, A.N., 1866-1867 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      Letter/s to Israel, Fielder; McKim, James Miller; unknown
    - Rankine, W.M., December 24, 1867 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Reed, Henry L., February 17, 1866 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Reed, J.N., October 30, 1867 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Reid, Kate T., August 10, 1866 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      Application for a teaching position; Recommendation from Kendall, Simon B.
    - Remond, Charles L., September 12, 1844 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Rendall, J.N., May 1, 1867 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Renne, Zelma H., 1866-1869 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Renwick, R., January 18, 1868 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Reynolds, John T., June 30, 1866 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      Application for a teaching position
    - Rhoads, James Evans, 1866-1867 (Box 23, Folder 12)
      Letter/s to H.B. Holmes; McKim, James Miller
      Oliver, Mary Ellen
    - Rhodes, Samuel, February 7, 1866 (Box 23, Folder 13)
      Letter/s to Mr. Cadbury
    - Richards, Sarah V., Undated (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Richardson, C.C., February 8, 1866 (Box 23, Folder 15)
      Letter/s to Deane, W.W.
    - Richmond, E.E., 1868-1869 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Richmond, Idella V., 1869 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Ricketson, Daniel, January 1871 (Box 23, Folder 18)
      Poem for Child, Lydia Maria
    - Ritchie, H., February 23, 1866 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Robert, Christopher Rhinelander, September 4, 1866 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Roberts, James B., March 16, 1866 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Miles, Robin, June 20, 1870 (Box 23, Folder 22)
      Itemized receipt for Madame Shaw
    - Robinson, M.R., November 28, 1860 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Rodgers, Joseph H., March 1867 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Rogers, D.F., Undated (Box 23, Folder 25)
      Letter/s to Austen, Willard
    - Rogers, E. Louise, April 5, 1866 (Box 23, Folder 26)
      Teacher's certificate
    - Root, Augustine, 1866-1867 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Rouviere, Fannie, Undated (Box 23, Folder 28)
      Recommendations for a teaching position from Parker, Edwin P.; Root, Horatio; Savage, Fannie E.; Swift, Rowland
    - Rushmore, Matilda, January 5, 1867 (Box 23, Folder 29)
      Letter/s to Greely, Horace
    - Russel, Sophie J., 1866-1867 (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Russell, Sarah L., Undated (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Russell, Thomas, 1867 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - Rust, Richard Sutton, 1866-1866 (Box 23, Folder 33)
      Letter/s to McKim, James Miller; includes a Coffin, Levi letter to John Morgan Walden
    - Rutherford, Ellen R., November 22, 1859 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Rutherford, William W., 1859-1866 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Sabin, Oscar C., 1866 (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Sabine, F.M., 1866 (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - St. John, Oliver S., 1866 (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - Sampson, Sarah A., August 27, 1867 (Box 23, Folder 39)
      Nellis, Maggie
    - Sawyer, Samuel, May 10, 1866 (Box 23, Folder 40)